by.me 2017-06-15

# Privacy Policy for the Homebyme service | HomeByMe

Dassault Systèmes SE, registered with the Commercial Registry of Versailles (France) under the number 322 306 440, located 10, rue Marcel Dassault 78140 Vélizy-Villacoublay, France (hereinafter “3DVIA”) processes Personal Data (as defined below) of people browsing the https://home.by.me website (the “Site”) and/or Homebyme application of 3DVIA (the “Services”).

This “Privacy Policy” lets You (as defined below) know how 3DVIA collects and uses Your Personal Data and how You can control its use.  
**1\. SCOPE OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY**

This Privacy Policy sets forth the principles and guidelines governing the protection of the Personal Data (as defined below) collected on or through the Site and Services and concerning the Site and Services visitors and users (“You” or “Your”).

Personal data (“Personal Data”) means any information relating to an identified or identifiable person. An identifiable person is a person who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identification number or to one or more factors specific to the person.

Non-Personal Data means any information that does not result in the identification of a person.

The Site and Services Terms of Use, which can be found at https://home.by.me/terms are incorporated into this Privacy Policy. Your use of the Site and Services and any Personal Data You provide on the Site or through the Services are subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy and those Terms of Use.

**  
2\. DATA COLLECTED**

In order to use certain functions and features of the Site and Services, 3DVIA requires that You provide certain Personal Data when visiting or using the Site and Services. Personal Data likely includes:  
• first and last name,  
• date of birth or age,  
• postal address,  
• email address,  
• telephone number(s),  
• login (username) and password,  
• company, company size, department and job title,  
• profile description, social media links  
• Internet Protocol (IP) address  
• financial data (credit card number and expiry date, name and address of the cardholder) and  
• any other Data as may be relevant for the purposes listed below.

In all cases, however, the Personal Data gathered is limited to data necessary to the purposes described under Article 4.

You are free to decide whether or not to provide all or part of Your Personal Data. However, if You choose not to provide all or part of this Personal Data, the purposes as described in Article 4 hereafter might not be achieved or not properly achieved, some areas and functions of the Site and Services may not function properly and/or You may be refused access to certain pages on the Site or certain functionalities of the Services. In particular, You will not be authorized to save your projects, purchase products or services via the Site or Services.

In addition, we may use Non-personal data such as the number of “likes”, number of space planning projects, number of rooms planed, planned surface in square meters, products chosen on the Site to plan spaces etc., either for statistical purposes, or to inform our partners which of their products are used and how such products are used.  
**3\. PROTECTION OF PERSONAL DATA CONCERNING CHILDREN**

3DVIA products are not marketed to children under the age of 13 and 3DVIA does not knowingly collect, conserve or store Personal Data or Non-Personal Data from children under the age of 13. 3DVIA is committed to protecting the privacy of children and if 3DVIA becomes aware that such information was collected, it will treat that information as sensitive.  
**4\. METHODS AND PURPOSES OF COLLECTION OF PERSONAL DATA**

As stated above, You provide Your Personal Data on a voluntary basis.

3DVIA will collect Personal Data either online or offline and this Privacy Policy is applicable regardless of the means of collection. In the case of online collection, this Privacy Policy is posted on the Site and in the case of offline collection, You will be notified this Privacy Policy.

Personal Data is generally collected to carry out the business of 3DVIA, such as improving 3DVIA’s marketing and advertising efforts, better tailoring 3DVIA products and services to customers’ needs or complying with reporting obligations required by law, and similar activities.

Your Personal Data collected by 3DVIA on or through the Site and Services is used by 3DVIA for the following purposes:  
• To enable You to create projects and request information;  
• To provide You with a personalised interactive use of the Site and Services;  
• To ascertain Your requirements and interests and provide You with the most suitable products and/or services;  
• To allow You to open and maintain an account in order to obtain specialized documentation and technical assistance;  
• To enable You to subscribe to a commercial or support-type service;  
• To enable You to make online purchases of some of our products;  
• To access all the features and options offered by the Site and Services; and  
• Any other purposes associated with the above purposes.

By providing Your e-mail address, You hereby expressly authorize, 3DVIA and its subsidiaries to use it together with other relevant Personal Data to send You commercial or marketing messages.

3DVIA might also use Your email address for administrative or other non-marketing purposes (for example, to notify You significant changes to the Site and Services).

The projects that You have created through the Site and saved in Your account are automatically published on the Site, in order to enable visitors and other users to see and understand how the 3DVIA services can be used, and enable them to tag your projects with a “like”. Each of Your projects will be associated to Your username and country of residence, which will be visible to visitors and other users. You expressly authorize 3DVIA to publish on the Site Your projects, associated with Your username and country of residence. The comments you post on the Site are associated to Your username.

The Site provides You with public forums where You can post comments associated to your username. Please note that any information that you share on such public forums will become accessible to anyone; we therefore recommend You to be cautious as to which information you disclose. 3DVIA may use Your comments published on our Site regarding the Homebyme service for publication purposes, in press articles or other media, in marketing materials and/or in social networks.

**  
5\. COOKIES**

Cookies are text files stored and used to record non-personal and personal information concerning Your browsing of the Site.

3DVIA may use cookies or other technologies that may collect or store Personal Data to improve services for You through, for example:  
• enabling a service to recognize your device so You don’t have to give the same information several times during one task,  
• recognizing that You may already have given a username and password so you don’t need to do it for every web page requested,  
• measuring how many people are using services, so they can be made easier to use and there’s enough capacity to ensure they are fast,  
• analyzing data to help 3DVIA understand how people interact with the Services so 3DVIA can enhance the Services or optimize Your user experience and content to better reflect Your needs and interests.

3DVIA uses two types of cookies: permanent cookies and temporary cookies. Temporary cookies disappear as soon as You log off from the Site. Permanent cookies remain after logging off from the Site in order to be used on subsequent visits to the Site.

You will be notified the first time You receive a cookie, and then You decide whether to accept it or refuse it. By continuing to use the Site in consideration of the above, You expressly authorize 3DVIA to use such cookies.

You can also configure Your browser software to refuse all cookies; if You do so, however, some areas and features of the Site may not function properly and/or You may not access some parts or services of the Site.

When you navigate through the Site, some information may also be collected through the use of other technologies, such as Internet tags or web beacons, and/or the collection of navigational data (log files, server logs, clickstream data).

Your Internet browser will then automatically send 3DVIA such information, such as the URL of the website that you just came from, the Internet Protocol (IP) address and the browser version your computer is currently using, your clickstream on the website (pages that you have visited, paths taken on the site etc.).

3DVIA may use your information collected through the Site in order to manage your account, improve the content of our website and our service, communicate information to you (if you have requested such information), for our research and marketing needs, for statistical purposes and/or to identify the products and services that the users are interested in.

3DVIA may also use third party vendors to measure and analyze the effectiveness of the Site and the Services (third parties such as Google that are specialized in web analytics, to measure the traffic) or to analyze Your use of the Site and Services in order to optimize Your user experience and content to better reflect Your needs and interests; in such a case, web beacons and cookies provided by such third party vendors may be used and stored.

**  
6\. PERSONAL DATA PROCESSING AND STORAGE TERM**

Processing of Personal Data includes using, storing, recording, transferring, adapting, summarizing, amending, reporting, sharing and destroying Personal Data as necessary under the circumstances or as otherwise required by law.

All Personal Data that will have been collected will be stored for a limited duration that is relevant to the purpose of such collection and for so long as required by applicable law.

**  
7\. LINKS TO WEBSITES NOT CONTROLLED BY 3DVIA OR ITS SUBSIDIARIES**

This Site and the Services might offer links to third party Websites which may be of interest to You.

Unless 3DVIA receives Your express authorization, 3DVIA does not share any Personal Data with these third parties. However, 3DVIA may provide them with Non-Personal Data.

These third parties use technological processes to send advertisements and links appearing on the Site to Your browser software, via Your IP address. They may also use other technologies (such as cookies, JavaScript or web beacons) to assess the effectiveness of their advertisements and to personalize their content.

3DVIA does not exercise any control over the content of third party Websites or the practices of these third parties in connection with the protection of Personal Data that they might collect and are thus not in the control of 3DVIA. Consequently, 3DVIA declines all liability for the content of third party websites or the practices of these third parties concerning the protection of Personal Data.

It is therefore Your responsibility to inform yourself as to these third parties’ privacy policies.

**  
8\. TRANSFER/SHARING OF PERSONAL DATA**

If You are accessing the Site and Services from a location outside of the European Union, with laws or regulations governing data collection, use, and disclosure that differ from European Union, please note that through Your continued use of the Site and Services, which are governed by French law, the corresponding Terms of Use and this Privacy Policy, You are transferring Your Personal Data to the European Union and You consent to that transfer.

As a company belonging to a global group, 3DVIA is able to use available technology to efficiently manage Personal Data and obtain such Personal Data online or otherwise throughout its international operations. Personal Data may be collected through the Site and Services and subsequently disclosed to and used by an affiliate of 3DVIA (“3DVIA Group Companies”) for the purposes stated in Article 4 of this Privacy Policy.

Please note that 3DVIA may transfer Your Personal Data outside of the European Union, as long as before transferring Your Personal Data, 3DVIA has ascertained that non European Union entities offer an adequate level of protection in accordance with European legislation.

Where 3DVIA has knowledge that a third party to which 3DVIA has provided Personal Data for the purposes listed in Article 4 above, is using or disclosing Personal Data contrary to this Privacy Policy or to applicable laws, 3DVIA will take reasonable steps to prevent or stop such use or disclosure.

You will have the opportunity to decide whether You authorize 3DVIA to use Your Personal Data for a purpose differing from the purpose for which it was originally collected.

3DVIA will also disclose Personal Data to third parties if 3DVIA determines that such disclosure is necessary for technical reasons (such as hosting services by a third party) or to protect 3DVIA’s legal interests (such as in the event of acquisition or merger by a third company or total or partial liquidation of 3DVIA). These transfers may be transmitted over the internet, via mail, via facsimile, or by any other method which 3DVIA determines is appropriate and in accordance with applicable law.

3DVIA may also disclose Your Personal Data to carefully selected partners who offer products and services that may be of interest to You, provided that You have expressly agreed to receive such offers. In such a case, 3DVIA requires its partners to process Your Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy and use it for the same purposes. You can at any time object to the use of Your Personal Data for such purposes, without any charge or justification, by clicking on the link that will be provided to You at the bottom of each email that You receive.  
**9\. RIGHT OF ACCESS TO AND RECTIFICATION OF THE DATA**

3DVIA will take reasonable steps to ensure that the Personal Data collected is used for the purposes stated in this Privacy Policy and that such Personal Data is correct and up to date.

You have a right to access Your Personal Data. In addition, You have a right to request the rectification, completion, update or erasure of Your Personal Data. You also have a right to obtain a copy of the Personal Data conserved by 3DVIA.

If You have an account, You can exercise Your rights of access to and rectification of the Personal Data by logging on to Your account. Otherwise, You may exercise Your rights of access to and rectification of the data by sending an email to the following address: mkt@homebyme.com.

Depending on the scope of the request, 3DVIA reserves the right to charge a reasonable fee to cover any out-of-pocket costs incurred in connection with such access, modification and deletion of Personal Data. 3DVIA may deny access to Personal Data in limited circumstances, defined by applicable laws and regulations.  
**10\. DATA SECURITY AND RECIPIENTS**

3DVIA undertakes to ensure the protection and security of Personal Data that You choose to communicate, in order to ensure the confidentiality of Your Personal Data and prevent Your Personal Data from being distorted, damaged, destroyed or disclosed to unauthorized parties.

3DVIA maintains reasonable physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to protect Personal Data from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alternation and destruction. As part of those safeguards, 3DVIA employs sophisticated technology designed to protect Personal Data during its transmission and prevent transmission errors or unauthorized acts of third parties. However, while 3DVIA strives to protect Your Personal Data, in light of the inevitable risks of data transmission over the internet, 3DVIA cannot guarantee full protection against any error occurring during the course of Personal Data transmission which is beyond 3DVIA ‘s reasonable control.

Since all Personal Data is confidential, access is limited to employees, contractors and agents of 3DVIA or 3DVIA Group Companies who have a need to know such data in carrying out their tasks. All the people who have access to Your Personal Data are bound by a duty of confidentiality and subject to disciplinary actions and/or other sanctions if they fail to meet these obligations.

However, it is important for You to exercise caution to prevent unauthorized access to Your Personal Data. You are responsible for the confidentiality of Your password and information appearing on Your account. Consequently, You must ensure that You log out of Your session in the event of shared use of a computer.

**11\. DISPUTE RESOLUTION**

Although 3DVIA has put in place reasonable safeguards to protect Personal Data, we recognize that there is no method of transmitting or storing Personal Data that is completely secure.

However, 3DVIA is committed to ensure the privacy of Personal Data: if You have a reason to believe that the security of Your Personal Data has been compromised or misused, You should contact 3DVIA via the following address: mkt@homebyme.com.

3DVIA will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints regarding use and disclosure of Personal Data in accordance with the principles contained in this Privacy Policy.

Unauthorized access to Personal Data or the improper use of Personal Data may constitute offences under local law and under the regulations in force within each company in the 3DVIA group.  
**12\. CONTACT**

For any additional question concerning this Privacy Policy, or any request for rectification, completion, update, or deletion of Your Personal Data You may send an email to the following address: mkt@homebyme.com.  
**13\. DATE OF ENTRY INTO FORCE OF THE PRIVACY POLICY AND CHANGES TO IT**

This Privacy Policy may be updated according to 3DVIA’s requirements and circumstances, or where required by applicable laws and regulations.

Last modification: This Privacy Policy was modified on November 2015.
